I should've known... this would happen.
But... I had no other choice but to rely on you.
Armin...
Why... don't you run away?
A Titan?
Shit!
You just try coming closer!
Make one move to take him and he's dead!
What's that?
He's got... Titan marks around his eyes.
Is he the Beast Titan?!
Are you...
...Eren Jaeger?
If nothing else, I'm taking him with me!
You look nothing like your father.
What?
Believe me, I know what you're going through.
We're both victims of your father.
You've... been brainwashed by him.
My... dad?
Argh... You're kidding me!
He chased me all the way here?
Let's call it a draw, Levi.
We're in no shape to fight.
Bertholdt...
I'm sorry, but I think it's the end for you.
Eren! Someday, I'm coming back to rescue you!
He ran?
Captain!
That was the last of my gas.
I'll chase him! Hand over your gas and blades!
Right!
Hurry!
Reiner... What's this metal case
you had in your left chest pocket?
Before we chopped off all your limbs,
you tried to grab it with
the strength you had left.
Suicide pills? Or perhaps a bomb?
Ouch!
Sorry.
A letter...
A letter?
What kind of letter?
A letter... from Ymir.
You have to... give it... to Christa...
Only after we've inspected it.
Now then. I've got a mountain
of questions for you, but...
Your lips seem as tight as your armor is hard.
Are you going to cooperate and tell us
everything that we want to know?
No.
Thanks. It helps that you're prepared for this.
Hold on!
Are you sure? We might be able
to steal his power.
Today, I would like to explain...
...how we're going to get
maximum value from this injection.
Using this medicine, the Colossal
Titan's, the Armored Titan's,
or the Beast Titan's powers can be stolen.
As for how...
The one injected with this will become a Titan
and eat someone who can change
into a Titan like Eren can.
By doing so, although they would
initially be a Titan lacking intelligence,
they would revert into a human
able to wield that Titan's powers.
If this is achieved, not only do we gain
information regarding Titan powers,
we're also able to revive a person
on the brink of death.
If you capture an enemy with
Titan powers, sever all their limbs.
And when it is safe to do so,
summon Captain Levi.
We have only this one injection.
I'm entrusting Captain Levi
with the call to use it.
I don't think all the conditions
for that have been met.
We don't know the situation
with Levi and the other side.
Neither do we have the time
to go confirm it ourselves.
Reason being, there's no way for us
to gauge the full depth of their powers!
Even if I cut his head off,
we can't be too sure!
This isn't like you, Hange.
If we back down because
of not knowing something,
down the line, can we ever
hope to beat the Titans?
Jean...
When are we ever going to know
all there is about the enemy?
Mikasa.
Yeah?
How much gas do you have?
It's almost entirely gone.
But it should be enough to reach
Eren and Armin at least.
That's more than me.
Mikasa... I need you to go
check out their situation.
Fill up your gas and bring back
the injection from Levi.
If for any reason you're unable
to do so, fire a smoke signal.
That will be my signal to end Reiner.
Affirmative.
Hange, I--
The decision was mine.
You were just a factor.
Why... did I?
After all this time, am I actually...?
Yeah! Keep it up!
Armin's breathing again!
Come on! Just keep on breathing!
Armin?
Captain! Get the syringe!
Make Armin into a Titan and
we'll have him eat Bertholdt!
Hurry up and inject him!
Yeah...
Hange!
Not good!
Reiner was taken! Hange!
Shit!
Conny! Don't chase!
We hardly have any gas left.
You'll just end up getting killed.
Shit!
It's my fault...
I've... done something terrible...
I said the decision was mine.
Let's regroup with the others.
Captain... Levi...
I finally found you.
Commander Erwin is badly wounded!
His stomach is gouged...
and his organs are demolished!
The blood just won't stop!
I thought that injection
might be able to help, but...
What do you think?
Huh?
Captain?
He's... still breathing.
He's... alive.
I'm using the injection... on Erwin.
You said...
...you'd use it on Armin!
I'm... reviving the one who can save humanity.
Reiner... You were incredibly lucky.
"Not only can Titan powers and much-needed information
be stolen by using the injection, but it also allows
the revival of someone who is critically wounded.
The ideal candidate would be someone near death."
You guys...
Do you have the faintest damn clue...
...what you're doing?
It's Erwin...
The commander of the Scouts.
And you're saying to watch him die.
There's no time for this.
Stay out of my way.
Keep your emotions out of this.
Keep my... emotions out?
Tell me... How come you didn't
hand over the syringe right away?!
Because I was considering the
possibility Erwin might still be alive.
You couldn't have known Floch
would drag the commander here!
There's just no way you knew!
You're right, but...
The fact that Erwin is now here
means I use it on him.
Hey!
His strength isn't all there!
I can take it from him by force!
You should know as well as I do!
Without Erwin's talent,
humanity can't beat the Titans!
That's right, Mikasa! Let's stop
with this madness already!
It's... no different if we lose... Armin.
Eren!
Hasn't it... always been like that?
He's the reason why we saved
Trost by plugging it with a rock.
He revealed Annie's identity.
It was Armin who came up with
the idea of moving at night!
The only reason we uncovered
Reiner's hiding spot...
...and the only reason we defeated Bertholdt...
...was all because of Armin!
The one who's gonna save humanity
isn't me or the commander!
It's Armin!
Isn't that right, Mikasa?!
Please give it to me!
The one who will save humanity...
is Commander Erwin.
Shut up!
I will not shut up.
Don't think you're the only
ones who've had it tough!
You might not know, but...
On the other side of that wall,
there's not a single living soldier.
Everyone died when the Beast
Titan threw boulders at us.
I didn't think anyone could be saved...
But Commander Erwin was the only exception.
He thought of a plan for us
to bite back at the Beast Titan...
...and we did.
We were smashed to bits just as planned.
And I'm sure the last thing they felt...
...was fear.
When I found the commander alive,
I was about to finish him off.
But... that's going too easy on him.
I thought to myself that he ought
to taste more of this hell.
And then... I understood.
The only one who can lay waste
to the Titans... is a devil!
And if I can bring back the devil,
that must be my mission in life!
That has to be why I survived like
a coward when everyone else died!
So stay out of his way!
Don't do it!
Hange...
Hey... You've got to be... kidding me...
No way...
You can't... be serious...
Mikasa! You have to know
how much we need Erwin!
We can't let the flames of hope
extinguish inside the walls!
But... Armin could... do that, too!
It's true, Armin is exceptional...
But he doesn't have Erwin's
experience and leadership!
There are people I want to bring back, too.
Hundreds of them.
I've had to say farewell since
the day I joined the Scouts.
Hange!
But...
You know, don't you?
No matter who it is,
there comes a day to say farewell.
I know it's impossible,
but you have to accept this.
There will be times you can't keep your sanity.
It's tough.
Very tough.
I know.
Even so, we have to keep moving forward.
Captain...
Do you... know about... the sea?
No matter how far you look,
it stretches past the horizon.
It's a gigantic lake.
Armin said--
Hey! Cut it out!
There's a sea beyond the walls...
...and he said we'd go there together!
But... that was our dream since we
were little, and I forgot it long ago!
Avenging my mom... Killing the Titans...
The only thoughts in my head are full of hate!
But... he's not like that!
Armin cares about more than just fighting!
He has dreams!
Everyone get out of here!
I'm going to have Erwin eat Bertholdt!
Come on. Let's go, Mikasa.
Shit... Shit...!
Armin...
See you...
Let's start by seeing the sea!
You'll see! It does exist!
If this dream of yours comes true...
...what will you do then?
I don't know. I won't know until it happens.
I...
I want to go to the basement.
Good grief.
They're all the same...
Whining like brats one after another...
Everyone had to be drunk on
somethin' to keep pushing on...
Everyone... was a slave to somethin'.
But there's more than that.
The sea...
Erwin!
Teacher...
How do we know there're not more humans...
...outside the walls?
Give up on your dream and die.
Lead the recruits straight into hell.
Everyone had to be drunk on
somethin' to keep pushing on...
I will take down the Beast Titan.
Levi...
Thank you.
Guys!
Help me!
Annie! Reiner!
Captain...
Why... did you...?
Do you think... you can forgive him?
He had no choice but to become a devil.
It was us who wished for that.
And in the end, when he had
finally been set free from hell,
we wanted to bring him back once more.
But I think... it's time to let him rest.
Erwin...
I promised I'd kill the Beast Titan, but...
It's going to have to wait.
He's... dead.
I see.
Armin is shaken after learning
of Bertholdt's and Erwin's deaths.
Eren heads towards that place his father,
Grisha, promised to show him.
Next episode: "The Basement."